Grief. Anger. Vengeance.
The Head Hunter is a horror, fantasy film directed by Jordan Downey.
On the outskirts of a kingdom, a quiet but fierce medieval warrior
protects the realm from monsters and the occult.
His gruesome collection of heads is missing only one - the
monster that killed his daughter years ago.
Driven by a thirst for revenge, he travels wild expanses on horseback.
When his second chance arrives, it’s in a way far
more horrifying than he ever imagined.
Father, played by Christopher Rygh.
Daughter, played by Cora Kaufman.
The Head (Voice), played by Aisha Ricketts.
The Head Hunter, originally titled The Head, is a 2018 American independent fantasy
horror film directed, written, produced and edited by Jordan Downey.
It stars Norwegian actor Christopher Rygh, Cora Kaufman, and Aisha Ricketts.
The film centers on the title character, who works as a bounty hunter for a local kingdom, all the
while he awaits the eventual return of the creature that murdered his daughter.
Influenced by Quest for Fire, The Witch, The X-Files, and Tales From the
Crypt, The Head Hunter was developed by Downey and Kevin Stewart.
The filming location was decided long before the story was developed.
The concept was developed at a writer's retreat, in which the filmmakers had assembled and hosted
at Stewart's family home in Soutelo Mourisco, a small village in Northern Portugal.
Rygh, in his feature-film debut, was cast in the leading role after
the filmmakers discovered him on a casting website.
Principal photography began in Bragança, Portugal, while
additional scenes were shot in Norway, and California.
The Head Hunter premiered at the Sitges Film Festival on October 6,
2018, as a part of the "Panorama Fantàstic" section.
While the film was screened under the title The Head at Sitges and Nightmares Film
Festival, but was later changed to The Head Hunter due to lukewarm reactions.
The film received several awards and nominations at various film festivals and received positive reviews from critics upon its release, with
many praising the film's atmosphere, cinematography, and Rygh's performance, although its low budget prompted some criticism.
The film explores themes of monster, grave, castle, woods, revenge.
The tone is dark.